RG 123:001, Daughters of the American Revolution, Ruth Wyllys Chapter (Hartford, Conn.)
Connecticut State Library
Daughters of the American Revolution, Ruth Wyllys Chapter records
1778-1989
bulk 1892-1989
1892-1989
Connecticut State Library
Daughters of the American Revolution. Ruth Wyllys Chapter (Hartford, Conn.)
6 cubic feet
The Ruth Wyllys Chapter of Hartford, Connecticut, was organized November 18, 1892, and chartered January 6, 1893. Its members named it for Ruth Wyllys representing George, Samuel, Hezekiah and John Palsgrave Wyllys, statesmen and Revolutionary War officers.
RG123_001
Multiple
Historical Note
The Daughters of the American Revolution (DAR) is a patriotic organization whose objects are perpetuating the memory and spirit of the patriots of the American Revolution and teaching the ideals of American institutions and the duties of the American citizenship to the upcoming generation.
The Ruth Wyllys Chapter of Hartford, Connecticut, was organized November 18, 1892, and chartered January 6, 1893. Its members named it for Ruth Wyllys representing George, Samuel, Hezekiah and John Palsgrave Wyllys, statesmen and Revolutionary War officers.
Scope and Content
The records include annual reports, applications for membership, historical papers, minutes of meetings, scrapbooks, and treasurer’s records.
Related Material
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Daughters of the American Revolution. Ruth Wyllys Chapter (Hartford, Conn.)
Subjects:
Daughters of the American Revolution. Ruth Wyllys Chapter (Hartford, Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut -- Genealogy
Document Types:
Application forms; Correspondence; Essays; Financial records; Minutes; Pamphlets; Reports
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
Various officers deposited original and photostat records with the Connecticut State Library.
Container List
- Records, 1778, 1869-1989
  - 1940-004
    - 1. Minutes, 1892-1960; 1966-1989; 18 volumes
      The volume(s) for 1960-1966 is not present.
      Volumes include list of members and also consist of by-laws and constitution. General and Executive minutes are interspersed except for volume 1.
      Volumes numbered on title page.
      - Volume 1, 1892 November 18-1896 October 31 (Box 1)
        Book in reverse: minutes of Executive meeting, 1892 December 8-1896 October 31.
      - Volume 2 & 3, 1896 December 7-1900 April 27 (Box 1)
        Volume 2, 1896 December 7-1899 October 31; volume 3, 1899 December 12-1900 April 27.
      - Volume 4, 1900 May 19-1903 April 27; 2 copies (Box 1)
      - Volume 5, 1903 June 11-1906 April 27 (Box 1)
      - Volume 6, 1906 may 17-1909 April 27 (Box 1)
      - Volume 7, 1909 May 28-1912 April 27 (Box 1)
      - Volume 8, 1912 June 13-1915 April 27 (Box 1)
      - Volume 9, 1915 May 18-1917 November 17 (Box 1)
      - Volume 10, 1917 November 17-1918 April 27 (Box 1)
        Page in front of title page states volume 3.
      - Volume 11, 1918 May 29-1921 April 27 (Box 1)
      - Volume 12, 1921 May 26-1924 October 23 (Box 1)
      - Volume 13, 1924 October 31-1927 June 9 (Box 1)
      - Volume 14, 1927 October 4-1932 May 12 (Box 1)
      - Volume 15, 1932 September 27-1940 October 31 (Box 1)
      - Volume 16, 1940 December 6-1949 April 28 (Box 2)
      - Volume 17, 1949 May 12-1960 May 25 (Box 2)
      - Volume 18, 1966 December 1-1976 June 9 (Box 2)
      - Volume 19, 1976 September 8-1989 September 21 (Box 2)
    - 2. Membership roll, 1901 September; 1 volume (Box 2)
      With changes to 1905.
    - 3. Collector's accounts, 1911-1914; 3 volumes (Box 2)
      2 volumes cover 1911-1914, 1 volume covers 1911-1912.
    - 4. Treasurer's accounts, 1892-1914; 6 volumes (Box 2)
      - 1892-1899, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1900-1905, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1905-1907, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1908-1911, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1911-1913, 1 volume (Box 2)
      - 1913-1914, 1 volume (Box 2)
    - 5. Correspondence and lists, 1901-1902 (Box 3)
    - 6. Annual reports, 1936-1940 (Box 3)
      Includes programs, pamphlets, photos, etc.
    - 7. Historical sketches, 1894-1938, undated (Box 3)
      Prepared for the History Study Group.
      - Scrapbook of conference of state chapters, 1894 May 16 (Box 3)
      - Fanny Olmstead manuscripts, undated (Box 3)
      - Reports of the 45th and 46th Continental Congress, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
      - Reports of the 10th, 11th, and 12th Congress, 1901-1903; 1 volume (Box 3)
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Ruth Wyllys Chapter, 1894; 1 pamphlet (Box 3)
      - Some incidents in the Early History of New London / by Augustus Brandegee (Box 3)
      - In memoriam Sara Thompson Kinney, 1923 (Box 3)
      - Souvenir of the Connecticut State Building at the Louisiana Purchase Exposition at St. Louis, 1904 (Box 3)
      - How Washington makes us think of the church ... A supplement to George Washington: Christian / by the Rev. John S. Littell, 1916; A copy is available at (Box 3)
      - Wyllys Family crest, photos, flag, undated (Box 3)
      - Ruth Wyllys Chapter Daughters of the American Revolution Historical Party, undated (Box 3)
      - Farewell Dinner to Mrs. Sara T. Kinney (program), 1909 June 23 (Box 3)
      - The Old Glebe House at Woodbury and its historic background / by George T. Linsley, 1926 October (Box 3)
        A copy is available at
      - Charter of the Colony of Connecticut 1662 / printed by Case, Lockwood & Brainard Company, 1900 (Box 3)
      - The episcopate of Bishop Seabury: his ecclesiastical statesmanship, his doctrinal leadership, his liturgical scholarship / by George T. Linsley, 1925 September (Box 3)
      - Work of the Connecticut Daughters of the American Revolution / by Mrs. Charles H. Bissel, State Regent, undated (Box 3)
      - Ruth Wyllys Chapter, D.A.R. in World War I / by Miss Florence Marcy Crofut, 1 envelope (Box 3)
        - D.A.R. Service Records World War, 1914-1919, Ruth Wyllys Chapter Daughters of the American Revolution Connecticut Chapter, No. 3 (Box 3)
        - Presentation of Volume of World War Service Records to Ruth Wyllys Chapter, Daughters of the American Revolution, 1925 October 31 (Box 3)
      - Papers compiled and read by members of the History Study Group of Ruth Wyllys Chapter during seasons 1939-1940 & 1940-1941, Mrs. William Maltbie Historian, 1 envelope (Box 3)
    - 8. Registrar's records, 1892-1967; 13 volumes
      Applications for membership.
      By application number.
      - 1-100, 1892-1893 (Volume Volume 1)
      - 101-200, 1893-1896 (Volume Volume 2)
      - 201-300, 1896-1903 (Volume Volume 3)
      - 301-400, 1903-1910 (Volume Volume 4)
      - 401-500, 1910-1914 (Volume Volume 5)
      - 501-600, 1914-1917 (Volume Volume 6)
      - 601-700, 1917-1920 (Volume Volume 7)
      - 701-800, 1920-1923 (Volume Volume 8)
      - 801-900, 1924-1927 (Volume Volume 9)
      - 901-1000, 1927-1936 (Volume Volume 10)
      - 1001-1100, 1936-1948 (Volume Volume 11)
      - 1101-1200, 1948-1954 (Volume Volume 12)
      - 1201-1300, 1955-1967 (Volume Volume 13)
    - 9. Col. Samuel Webb's Regiment, 1778 October; negative photostat (Oversize Oversize item)
      Payroll of Capt. Charles Whiting Co.
    - 10. Scrapbooks, 1911-1934; 2 volumes
      Newspaper clippings on D.A.R. activities.
      - 1911-1921, 1 volume (Box Item)
      - 1921-1934, 1 volume (Box Item)
  - SL154647
    - Scrapbook, 1869-1899 (Box Item)
  - 1992-044
    - War Service Records, 1914-1921, Connecticut Daughters of the American Revolution (Box Shared box)
      Indexes to questionnaires
  - 1993-058
    - War Service Records World War 1914-1919, Ruth Wyllys Chapter Daughters of American Revolution No. 3 (Box Shared box)
      Copy is in box 3 of accession 1940-004
  - 2002-061
    - War Service Records World War I, 1914-1919, Ruth Wyllys Chapter Daughters of the American Revolution, 1 volume, negative photostat (Box Item)
  - 2002-062
    - War Service Records World War II, 1939-1945, Ruth Wyllys Chapter Daughters of the American Revolution, 1 volume, negative photostat (Box Item)
  - 2004-032
    - Regents notebook, 1949-1952 (Box Shared box)